Preliminary guide to the Warren Mcgee collection 1890-1998
Montana Historical Society Research Center
- Warren McGee
  - Subject Files
    - Park County Senior Citizens (correspondence, minutes, newsletters, clippings), 1979-1992 (Box-folder 11 / 32)
    - Passenger train image and service: clippings, 1961-1992 (Box-folder 11 / 33-36)
    - Passenger train reductions: clippings, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 11 / 37)
    - People: clippings (re interesting people, some famous, some not; some national, some local), 1974-1997 (Box-folder 11 / 38-39)
    - Planes, ships, Navy, Army: clippings [unsorted], 1968-1972 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
    - Political: Montana Democratic Party (circulars), 1969? (Box-folder 12 / 2)
    - Political personalities: Forrest Anderson (clippings), 1971-1974 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
    - Political personalities: Tim Babcock (clippings), 1965-1974 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
    - Political personalities: James Battin (clippings), 1966-1969 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
    - Political personalities: Walter T. Hickel (clippings), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 12 / 6)
    - Political personalities: Chet Huntley (clippings), 1970 (Box-folder 12 / 7)
    - Political personalities: Lyndon B. Johnson (clippings), 1964-1968 (Box-folder 12 / 8)
    - Political personalities: Thomas Judge (clippings), 1979-1982 (Box-folder 12 / 9)
    - Political personalities: Mike Mansfield (speeches in Congress re railroads), 1970-1973 (Box-folder 12 / 10)
    - Political personalities: John Melcher (clippings), 1967-1976 (Box-folder 12 / 11)
    - Political personalities: Lee Metcalf (clippings), 1961-1978 (Box-folder 12 / 12)
    - Political personalities: Lee Metcalf (speeches in Congress re railroads), 1968-1972 (Box-folder 12 / 13)
    - Political personalities: Harriet Miller (clippings), 1968-1972 (Box-folder 12 / 14)
    - Political personalities: Arnold Olsen (clippings), 1966-1976 (Box-folder 12 / 15)
    - Political personalities: Dick Shoup (clippings), 1970-1974 (Box-folder 12 / 16)
    - Political personalities: Robert L. Woodahl (clippings), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 12 / 17)
    - Political personalities: miscellaneous (clippings), 1961-1978 (Box-folder 12 / 18)
    - Politics: correspondence, flyers, etc., 1963-1972 (Box-folder 12 / 19)
    - Politics: Governor Tom Judge inaugural (invitations, etc.), 1973 (Box-folder 12 / 20)
    - Politics: clippings [McGee ran for Legislature in 1966], 1960-1972 (Box-folder 12 / 21-25)
    - Politics, economy, etc.: clippings [unsorted], 1971-1981 (Box-folder 12 / 26-29)
    - Politics, economy, etc.: clippings [unsorted], 1976-1983 (Box-folder 13 / 1-6)
    - Politics: Liquor Control Board (clippings), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
    - Politics: Livingston (letters, flyers, etc.), 1963-1970 (Box-folder 13 / 8)
    - Politics: Livingston (clippings), 1963-1971 (Box-folder 13 / 9-10)
    - Politics: national (clippings), 1964-1973 (Box-folder 13 / 11)
    - Pollution, including Garrison Phosphate plant: clippings, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 13 / 12)
    - Public lands: clippings, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 13 / 13)
    - Railpax: correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 13 / 14)
    - Railpax: legislation, resolutions, notices, etc., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 13 / 15)
    - Railpax: clippings, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 13 / 16-18)
    - Railroads: abandonments (clippings), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
    - Railroads: accident investigations, report # 4171-4174, summary report #10, 1970 (Box-folder 14 / 2)
    - Railroads: automation, employment, management (clippings), 1960-1974 (Box-folder 14 / 3)
    - Railroads: car accounting (clippings, weight listings, memos), 1960-1973 (Box-folder 14 / 4)
    - Railroads: employees (including opinion survey, Livingston [blank] and salary statistics, nationwide), 1960-1973 (Box-folder 14 / 5-6)
    - Railroads: foreign (clippings), 1961-1970 (Box-folder 14 / 7)
    - Railroads: history, preservation, etc. (clippings), 1965-1991 (Box-folder 14 / 8)
    - Railroads: innovation including car-train, BART, fast freight, etc. (clippings), 1960-1974 (Box-folder 14 / 9)
    - Railroads: labor-management relations (clippings), 1959-1974 (Box-folder 14 / 10)
    - Railroads: language (clippings), 1942 (Box-folder 14 / 11)
    - Railroads: locomotives (clippings), 1933-1974 (Box-folder 14 / 12-13)
    - Railroads: mergers (clippings), 1960-1977 (Box-folder 14 / 14-15)
    - Railroads: new lines (clippings), 1984-1995 (Box-folder 14 / 16)
    - Railroads: other railroads, including tourist lines, ConRail, etc. (clippings), 1984-1992 (Box-folder 14 / 17)
    - Railroads: safety (circular letters, etc.), 1960-1970 (Box-folder 14 / 18)
    - Railroads: safety, hot boxes (clippings), 1960-1968 (Box-folder 14 / 19)
    - Railroads: safety and train wrecks (clippings), 1960-1979 (Box-folder 14 / 20-22)
    - Railroads: service (clippings), 1965-1968 (Box-folder 14 / 23)
    - Railroads: strike (clippings), 1991 (Box-folder 14 / 24)
    - Railroads: stuff (clippings, miscellany) [unsorted] (Box-folder 14 / 25-26)
    - Railroads: timetables (Burlington Northern), 1970-1977 (Box-folder 14 / 27-28)
    - Railroads: timetables (Chicago, Burlington and Quincy), 1957 (Box-folder 14 / 29)
    - Railroads: timetables (Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific) [Milwaukee Road], 1950-1976 (Box-folder 14 / 30)
    - Railroads: timetables (Colorado and Southern), 1957 (Box-folder 14 / 31)
    - Railroads: timetables (Fort Worth and Denver), 1967 (Box-folder 14 / 32)
    - Railroads: timetables (Great Northern: various divisions), 1955-1968 (Box-folder 14 / 33-41)
    - Railroads: timetables [in 3 looseleaf binders and 3 folders (Box-folder 15 / 1-6)
    - Railroads: timetables (Milwaukee Road), 1942-1984 (Box-folder 16 / 1-3)
    - Railroads: timetables (miscellaneous) (Box-folder 16 / 4-5)
    - Railroads: tourist trains, including Centennial Train (brochures and clippings), 1986-1995 (Box-folder 16 / 6-7)
    - Railroads: miscellany [unsorted] (Box-folder 16 / 8)
    - Railroaders: clippings, 1938 (Box-folder 16 / 9)
    - Railway Brotherhoods of Montana: Joint Legislative Report, 1971 (Box-folder 16 / 10)
    - Recreation, conservation, etc.: clippings, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 16 / 11)
    - Republicans, Montana: clippings, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 16 / 12)
    - Snowmobiles: clippings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 16 / 13)
    - Spokane, Portland and Seattle Railway Historical Society: correspondence, brochures, constitution, etc., 1980s- 1990s? (Box-folder 16 / 14-15)
    - State lands, including coal and oil leases: clippings, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 16 / 16)
    - Steam locomotives list (by states), 1996 (Box-folder 16 / 17)
    - Taxes, including sales tax: clippings, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 16 / 18-20)
    - Train wrecks: correspondence, 1964, 1971 (Box-folder 16 / 21)
    - Train wrecks (Northern Pacific, Great Northern, Burlington Northern, and others, mostly Montana): clippings, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 16 / 22-23)
    - Train wrecks (Northern Pacific, Great Northern, Burlington Northern, and others, mostly Montana): clippings, 1983-1996 (Box-folder 17 / 1-3)
    - Train wrecks: clippings and photo provided by Les Schmidt, 1957-1991 (Box-folder 17 / 4)
    - Union Pacific Railway: history (clippings), 1950-1997 (Box-folder 17 / 5)
    - Union Pacific Railway: miscellany (Box-folder 17 / 6)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor press release (re rail worker protection plan), 1971 (Box-folder 17 / 7)
    - U.S. Interstate Commerce Commission: correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 17 / 8)
    - U.S. Interstate Commerce Commission: docket file (proposed merger to create Burlington Northern), 1968 (Box-folder 17 / 9)
    - U.S. Interstate Commerce Commission: clippings, 1960-1983 (Box-folder 17 / 10)
    - U.S. mail (railroad post offices): correspondence, circulars, etc., 1965-1973 (Box-folder 17 / 11)
    - U.S. mail (railroad post offices): legislation, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 17 / 12)
    - U.S. mail (railroad post offices): clippings, 1966-1982 (Box-folder 17 / 13-14)
    - United Transportation Union [UTU]: memos, contract, news update, 1970-1997 (Box-folder 17 / 15)
    - Vietnam War: clippings, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 17 / 16)
    - Washington Association of Railroad Passengers: brochures, etc., 1992 (Box-folder 17 / 17)
    - Water pollution, pesticides, etc.: clippings, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 17 / 18)
    - Wilderness: clippings, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 17 / 19)
    - Wildlife, recreation, mining...: clippings, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 17 / 20)
    - Wyoming coal and gas development: clippings, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 17 / 21)
    - Yellowstone National Park: brochures, 1898, 1967, 1969 (Box-folder 17 / 22)
    - Yellowstone National Park: clippings, 1960-1982 (Box-folder 17 / 23-24)
    - Yellowstone River: clippings (includes Yellowstone River Boat Float), 1968-1990 (Box-folder 17 / 25-26)
  - Miscellany
    - Cartoons (Box-folder 17 / 27)
    - Certificates, 1978-1998 (Box-folder 17 / 28)
    - Get-well cards, 1972 (Box-folder 17 / 29)
    - Greeting cards (birthdays, anniversaries, etc.), 1950s- 1990s (Box-folder 17 / 30-31)
    - Licenses (hunting, photo business, driver, voting, etc.), 1920s- 1980s (Box-folder 18 / 1)
    - Programs (reunions, meetings, etc.) (Box-folder 18 / 2)
    - Publications featuring McGee photos (Box-folder 18 / 3)
- Warren McGee's World War II Service
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letters home from basic training at Sheppard Field, Texas, Mar.-Apr. 1942 (Box-folder 18 / 4)
    - Letters home from Air Corps Technical School, Lincoln, Nebraska, Apr.-Sept. 1942 (Box-folder 18 / 5)
    - Letters home from Photo Mapping School, Colorado Springs Air Base, Colorado, Sept.-Dec. 1942 (Box-folder 18 / 6)
    - Letters home from 18th Combat Mapping Squadron, San Francisco, California, Dec. 1942 (Box-folder 18 / 7)
    - Letters home from 18th Combat Mapping Squadron, South Pacific [Espirito Santo, New Hebrides], Jan. 1943- Apr. 1944 (Box-folder 18 / 8-12)
    - Letters home from 18th Combat Mapping Squadron, Hawaii, May-July, 1944 (Box-folder 18 / 13)
    - Letters home from 18th Combat Mapping Squadron, South Pacific [Saipan, Marianas], July-Nov. 1944 (Box-folder 18 / 14)
    - Letters home from 18th Combat Mapping Squadron, Hawaii, Nov. 1944- Aug. 1945 (Box-folder 18 / 15-16)
    - Letters home from 18th Combat Mapping Squadron, South Pacific, Espirito Santa, New Hebrides, Saipan, Hawaii [smuggled out by friend past censor], Mar-June 1943, Mar. 1945 (Box-folder 18 / 17)
    - Postcard and photo sets sent home, 1945 (Box-folder 18 / 18)
  - General Correspondence
    - Letters from and to friends and relatives, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 18 / 19)
  - Miscellany
    - Military papers, orders, discharge, etc., 1941-1945 (Box-folder 18 / 20)
    - Training notes and tests: Air Corps Technical School, 1942 (Box-folder 18 / 21-22)
    - 13th Combat Mapping Squadron, Espirito Santo: roster, 1944 (Box-folder 18 / 23)
  - Clippings
    - World War II clippings and publications, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 18 / 24)
    - Scrapbook, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 18a / 1)
- Helen A. Lavold
  - Miscellany
    - Funeral service program, 1984 (Box-folder 18 / 25)
- Bernice Lavold MCGEE
  - Miscellany
    - Certificates, 1921-1995 (Box-folder 18 / 26)
    - School records, 1929-1934 (Box-folder 18 / 27)
- Howard E. and Mildred McGee
  - Miscellany
    - Certificate: Howard E. McGee, 1954 (Box-folder 18 / 28)
    - Clippings, miscellany, 1943-1982 (Box-folder 18 / 29)
    - Informal will: Mildred McGee, 1985 (Box-folder 18 / 30)
- Howard McGee [Son of Warren and Bernice McGee]
  - Miscellany
    - School records, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 18 / 31)
- Cooke City Transit Company
  - Organization
    - Articles of incorporation [photocopied from Secretary of State corporation records], 1918 (Box-folder 18 / 32)
  - Survey Records
    - Cooke-Gardner Railway survey books: A1-A2 (includes preliminary notes; preliminary transit line), 1918 (Box-folder 18 / 33)
    - Cooke-Gardner Railway survey books: B1,B3,B5 (includes survey; preliminary levels), 1918-1920 (Box-folder 18 / 34)
    - Cooke-Gardner Railway survey books: C1-C3 (includes survey; topographical notes) (Box-folder 18 / 35)
    - Cooke-Gardner road [?] survey for Republic Mines and Transit Company, 1920 (Box-folder 18 / 36)
- Unsorted
  - Miscellany
    - Clippings, publications, miscellany [unsorted] (Box-folder 19 /)